Six Sigma and the Role of Measurement
Welcome to this session as we look at the power of measurement.
In specific, we’re going to take a look at the role of measurement
in this area that we call Six Sigma.
This is a phenomenally important concept
where Six Sigma is concerned. We cannot over emphasize
the role of our ability to measure things.
Remember, it was Lord Kelvin told us in 1891.
If we cannot express what we know in the form of measurements,
then our knowledge is of a meager and unsatisfactory kind.
It's that simple. Now,
given that we can start to look at the idea that knowledge equals measurement.
In other words, we won't know something until we measure.
Therefore, knowledge and measurement are interconnected.
Especially, where we start to look at the idea of verifiable knowledge.
In other words, if we see some phenomena happen, like a UFO,
then we have to be able to measure it in order to make it verifiable knowledge.
Otherwise its not really knowledge, unless it's scientifically,
the key there is scientifically verifiable.
So as a result of that, if we have some experience Y.
And we have to be able to source trace it,
then we need to be able to measure Y and X.
To establish the relationship between Y and X.
For example, considering just a simple scatter diagram,
between the Y variable and the X variable.
We might collect X measurements, Y measurements, and relate those measurements
on a simple scatter diagram to look at the strength of association
between X and between Y.
In this case we see there is a positive relationship.
And we can fit a simple line through here, that's a line of best fit and say this.
If we constrain ourselves to this general range.
We project up and over.
Then we will get our output within this range.
If we stay X in this range,
we can see how that projects up and projects over.
Now, the only way that we can make that statement,
is if we're able to measure X and we're able to measure Y.
To establish the function. Y is a function of X. Without the ability to measure,
we couldn't establish such relationships.
This knowledge is verifiable, it’s repeatable.
We could go out and collect more measurements a second time
and see if the same knowledge results.
As we take progressive measurements and the same knowledge occurs
time, and time, and time again, then we can say that that knowledge is verified.
It’s therefore verifiable because we measure it.
And that is one reason that measurement is so important in the concept of Six Sigma.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.